Stephane Pion

"The further one goes, the less one knows" ;)

Greater Montreal Metropolitan Area

Summary

Stephane was a seasoned and experienced venture capitalist as well as a senior corporate manager. A strategic contract negotiator at the C-level, he had extensive Board level experience and was assumed senior executive operational responsibilities. He obtained a Ph.D. in Biomedical Sciences (Immunology) from the University of Montreal.

Specialties: Expertise range from Finance, raising capital in startups up to B rounds, debt financing, M&A activities, strategic business development negotiation, contract negotiations, executive roles, high technical knowledge with regards to IT and science.

Experience

Rhythm Capital Group

Managing Partner May 2012 - 2019 Montreal, Quebec

At Rhythm Capital Group, we offered advisory and operational services in the IT, Cleantech and Life science fields to companies, venture capital investors & other stakeholders needing expert advice or interim management solutions.

Through a transparent approach, our services could help build stronger companies from the pre-seed up to the commercialization stages.

Aligo Innovation, société en commandite

Director, Investments
June 2014 - October 2015

MSBi Valorisation

Investment Director August 2013 - June 2014 Montreal, Canada Area MSBi Valorisation (MSBiV) is an early stage group that provides capital, manpower and business sense to monetize promising technologies developed within McGill University, Université de Sherbrooke and Bishop's University and their affiliated research centres. We are instrumental for creating spin-offs as well as technology opportunities ready to be licensed to existing companies.

Institute of Cancer/CIHR

Assistant Director February 2011 - May 2012 Montréal, Quebec

As 2nd senior executive representing the Institute of Cancer, the assistant director is responsible for implementing all investment, operational and strategic decisions relating to cancer funding across Canada under the supervision of the Scientific Director;

Chronogen Inc.

President and Board Secretary December 2007 - September 2010 Montréal, Québec, Canada

Asked by shareholders to take on the role of president and secretary to divest assets in the context of an orderly shut-down of activities as well as to negotiate with secured debt holders and bankruptcy trustees.

Gestion T2C2/Bio Inc. And Gestion T2C2/Info Inc.

Associate

October 1998 - December 2009

Venture Capital Firm having \$160 M under management under three funds.

My responsibilities and accomplishments included:

Initiated and completed several multi-million dollar deals in the therapeutic and IT fields;

Proactively contributed as a director on several Boards of Directors of start-up companies;

Negotiated successfully several important agreements as diverse as licensing, corporate and financial;

Instrumental in negotiating with debt-holders and creditors prior to

arranging Companies Creditors Arrangements in several cases.

Bioaxone Therapeutics

Board Director January 2007 - December 2008 Montréal, Québec, Canada

Iatroquest Corp.

Board Director January 2004 - December 2008 Montreal, Canada Area

PainCeptor

Board Director February 2007 - December 2007 St-Laurent, Quebec

Novothera

Board Director January 2004 - December 2006

Compatigene

Board Director January 1999 - December 2005 Montreal, Quebec

Interim CEO 2000 - 2003 Montréal, Québec

Mandated by the Board to reposition a virtual academic company into an independent entity;

Managed a diverse team of 10 talented individuals in 2 productive R&D units;

Identified and approached several potential corporate acquisition partners;

Conceived, wrote and completed corporate packages including business

plan, scientific development plan and due diligence documents;

Negotiated and obtained an acquisition offer for the company; Bioaxone Therapeutics

Board Director January 2004 - December 2004

Executive board member

Converzyme

January 2000 - July 2003 Montréal, Québec Asked by the Board to help raise financing and strategic alliances. The company had no management, was scientifically focused and therefore my responsibilities encompassed the roles of operations, business development and negotiation of strategic alliances.

GBBC Inc.
Board Director
January 1998 - December 2001
Sherbrooke, Quebec, Canada

Education

Ph.D., Biomedical Sciences (Immunology), Biomedical Sciences (Immunology) · (1995 - 1998)

M.Sc., Biomedical sciences, Biomedical sciences · (1993 - 1995)

B.Sc., Microbiology and Immunology, Microbiology and Immunology · (1990 - 1993)

Collège Brébeuf
D.E.C., Sciences, Sciences · (1985 - 1989)

Collège des Eudistes
D.E.S., General · (1980 - 1985)